Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc. Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Hudson River Conservation Society Files, 1939 - 1959; 1; 19 linear feet 1 - 55 1 - 177
  - Hudson River - Geology (Folder 356, Box 27)
  - Hudson River - Maps (Folder 357, Box 27)
  - Hudson River - Zoning and Planning (Folder 358, Box 27)
  - Hudson River Basin Seminar (Folder 359, Box 27)
  - Hudson River Bend Area - Ad Hoc Committee (Folder 360, Box 27)
  - Hudson River Bend Area - Clippings (Folder 361, Box 27)
  - Hudson River Bend Area - Correspondence (Folder 362, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Bend Area - Meetings and Program Content (Folder 363, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Bend Area - Pure Waters Authority (Folder 364, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Dam near Chelsea, N.Y. (Folder 365, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Day Line (Folder 366, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Expressway (Folder 367, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Expressway - Hearings (Folder 368, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Fishermen’s Association, Inc. (Folder 369, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Guide (Folder 370, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Heritage (Folder 371, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Model Study (Folder 372, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Museum, Yonkers, N.Y. (Folder 373, Box 28)
  - “The Hudson River Needs Its Friends” (Folder 374, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Political Action Committee (Folder 375, Box 28)
  - The Hudson River Tourway (Folder 376, Box 28)
  - The Hudson River Sloop Restoration (Folder 377, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Valley Association, Inc. - Scrapbook (Folder 378, Box 28)
  - Hudson River Valley Bicentennial Goal Committee (Folder 379, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Clippings (Folder 380, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Correspondence (Folder 381, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Hearings (Folder 382, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Maps (Folder 383, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Newsletter (Folder 384, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Printed Materials (Folder 385, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission - Public Meeting 7/27/65 (Folder 386, Box 29)
  - Hudson River Valley Song (Folder 387, Box 30)
  - Hudson River Waterfronts (Folder 388, Box 30)
  - Hudson Valley Audubon Society (Folder 389, Box 30)
  - Hudson Valley Council (Folder 390, Box 30)
  - Hudson Valley Echoes - Theodore J. Cornu (Folder 391, Box 30)
  - Hudson Valley Survey (Folder 392, Box 30)
  - Hudson Valley Voice (Folder 393, Box 30)
  - Hunt, Rhoda Hinkley (Folder 394, Box 30)
  - Huntington House: A Proposed Junior Museum (Folder 395, Box 30)
  - Hyde Park, New York (Folder 396, Box 30)
  - I (Folder 397, Box 30)
  - Incinerator Plants (Folder 398, Box 30)
  - Industrial Resources Survey of Putnam County (Folder 399, Box 30)
  - Industrial Trends in the Hudson Valley (Folder 400, Box 30)
  - Industries Along the River (Folder 401, Box 30)
  - Innisfree Foundation (Folder 402, Box 30)
  - International Joint Commission - Niagara Falls (Folder 403, Box 30)
  - Interstate Planning Conference (Folder 404, Box 30)
  - Interstate Sanitation Commission - Pollution of the Hudson (Folder 405, Box 30)
  - Iona Island (Folder 406, Box 31)
  - Islands (Folder 407, Box 31)
  - J (Folder 408, Box 31)
  - Jacees Clean Water Action Kit (Folder 409, Box 31)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Interstate Cooperation (Folder 410, Box 31)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Mass Transportation (Folder 411, Box 31)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Natural Resources (Folder 412, Box 31)
  - K (Folder 413, Box 31)
  - Kelsey, Harlan P. (Folder 414, Box 31)
  - Kennedy Airport (Folder 415, Box 31)
  - Kingsland Point Park (Folder 416, Box 31)
  - Kingston Air Pollution (Folder 417, Box 31)
  - Kingston Branch (Folder 418, Box 31)
  - Kinkead - Young Property (Folder 419, Box 31)
  - Kord Company (Folder 420, Box 31)
  - L (Folder 421, Box 31)
  - Lakes, Ponds, and Reservoirs (Folder 422, Box 31)
  - Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (Folder 423, Box 31)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 424, Box 31)
  - Legislation (Folder 425, Box 32)
  - Legislative Committees (Folder 426, Box 32)
  - Legislature (Folder 427, Box 32)
  - Letters re: Mrs. Wightman’s Lectures (Folder 428, Box 32)
  - Lewis, Howard (Folder 429, Box 32)
  - Library of Congress (Folder 430, Box 32)
  - Lindenwald Preservation Committee (Folder 431, Box 32)
  - List of Houses to Visit on the East and West Shores of the Hudson (Folder 432, Box 32)
  - Little, Dr. Robert H. (Folder 433, Box 32)
  - Little Gardens Club of New York City (Folder 434, Box 32)
  - The Living Wilderness - Wilderness Society Quarterly (Folder 435, Box 32)
  - Local Planning and Zoning (Folder 436, Box 32)
  - Long Island Marine Wetlands (Folder 437, Box 32)
  - Luncheons to Organize Committees (Folder 438, Box 32)
  - Lydecker, Mrs. Wallace B. (Folder 439, Box 32)
  - Lyndhurst (Folder 440, Box 32)
  - M (Folder 441, Box 32)
  - McAllister, Mrs. Breck P. (Folder 442, Box 32)
  - The Malcolm Gordon School (Folder 443, Box 32)
  - Maps (Folder 444, Box 33)
  - Marinas (Folder 445, Box 33)
  - Marshes (Folder 446, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1937 - 1959 (Folder 447, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1960 - 1963 (Folder 448, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1964 (Folder 449, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1965 (Folder 450, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1966 (Folder 451, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1967 (Folder 452, Box 33)
  - Martin, Dudley 1968 (Folder 453, Box 34)
  - Martin, Dudley 1969 (Folder 454, Box 34)
  - Martin, Dudley 1970 -1977 (Folder 455, Box 34)
  - Martin, Dudley - Undated (Folder 456, Box 34)
  - Mathematical Methods in Chemical Engineering (Folder 457, Box 34)
  - Meetings (Folder 458, Box 34)
  - Membership (Folder 459, Box 34)
  - Membership Brochures (Folder 460, Box 35)
  - Membership Lists (Folder 461, Box 35)
  - Membership Polls re Hudson River Expressway and Dams on Upper Hudson (Folder 462, Box 35)
  - Memories of the Hudson (Folder 463, Box 35)
  - Mianus River Gorge Wildlife Refuge (Folder 464, Box 35)
  - The Mid- Hudson Area (Folder 465, Box 35)
  - Mid- Hudson Catskills Museum, New Paltz, N.Y. (Folder 466, Box 35)
  - Mid- Hudson Pattern for Progress, Inc. (Folder 467, Box 35)
  - Mid-Hudson Pattern for Progress Newsletter (Folder 468, Box 35)
  - Millbrook Garden Club (Folder 469, Box 35)
  - Minnewaska State Park (Folder 470, Box 35)
  - Minutes (Folder 471, Box 35)
  - Moodna Valley Association (Folder 472, Box 35)
  - Morgan, A. Kenneth (Folder 473, Box 35)
  - Mosler Safe Co. (Folder 474, Box 35)
  - Mt. Beacon (Folder 475, Box 35)
  - Mt. Taurus (Folder 476, Box 36)
  - Museum Village of Smith’s Clove (Folder 477, Box 36)
  - Museums and Art Centers (Folder 478, Box 36)
  - N (Folder 479, Box 36)
  - Nassau - Suffolk Business and Manufacturing (Folder 480, Box 36)
  - National Audubon Society (Folder 481, Box 36)
  - National Geographic Magazine (Folder 482, Box 36)
  - National Parks (Folder 483, Box 36)
  - National Council for Historic Sites and Buildings (Folder 484, Box 36)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation (Folder 485, Box 36)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation Quarterly (Folder 486, Box 36)
  - National Wildlife Federation (Folder 487, Box 36)
  - Natural Beauty Commission (Folder 488, Box 36)
  - Nature Conservancy (Folder 489, Box 37)
  - Neighborhood Garden Club, Shrub Oak (Folder 490, Box 37)
  - Nepera Chemical Co (Folder 491, Box 37)
  - Nevis (Folder 492, Box 37)
  - “The New Super Highways: Blessing or Blight?” (Folder 493, Box 37)
  - New Windsor Cantonment (Folder 494, Box 37)
  - New York Botanical Garden (Folder 495, Box 37)
  - New York Central Railroad (Folder 496, Box 37)
  - New York City - Natural Environment (Folder 497, Box 37)
  - New York Environmental News, October 1973 - April 1974 (Folder 498, Box 37)
  - New York Environmental News, May 1974 - June 1975 (Folder 499, Box 37)
  - New York - New Jersey Trail Conference (Folder 500, Box 37)
  - New York State Clean Air Committee (Folder 501, Box 38)
  - New York State Conservation Council (Folder 502, Box 38)
  - New York State Conservation Council - Legislative Reports (Folder 503, Box 38)
  - New York State Conservation Department (Folder 504, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (Folder 505, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Health (Folder 506, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Health - Bureau of Water Resource Services (Folder 507, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Health - Division of Pure Waters (Folder 508, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Health - Refuse Disposal Program (Folder 509, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Social Welfare (Folder 510, Box 38)
  - New York State Department of Transportation (Folder 511, Box 38)
  - New York State Department Plan - I (Folder 512, Box 38)
  - New York State Executive Department - Office for Local Government (Folder 513, Box 38)
  - New York State Historic Trust (Folder 514, Box 38)
  - New York State Historical Association (Folder 515, Box 38)
  - New York State Navigation Laws (Folder 516, Box 38)
  - New York State Parks (Folder 517, Box 39)
  - New York State Powerline Coalition (Folder 518, Box 39)
  - New York State Thruway Authority (Folder 519, Box 39)
  - New York State Vacationlands 1957 (Folder 520, Box 39)
  - New York State Telephone Company (Folder 521, Box 39)
  - New York Trap Rock Corporation (Folder 522, Box 39)
  - Newburgh-Beacon Bridge (Folder 523, Box 39)
  - Newburgh Branch (Folder 524, Box 39)
  - Newsletters 1940 - 1973 (Folder 525, Box 39)
  - Newspapers and Magazines (Folder 526, Box 39)
  - Newspaper Articles 1937 - 1943 (Folder 527, Box 39)
  - “The Next Decade” Conference - Steering Committee (Folder 528, Box 39)
  - Noise Pollution (Folder 529, Box 39)
  - North Bay Films (Folder 530, Box 39)
  - North River Navigator (Folder 531, Box 40)
  - Northway (Folder 532, Box 40)
  - Nyack, New York (Folder 533, Box 40)
  - O (Folder 534, Box 40)
  - Office Activities Committee (Folder 535, Box 40)
  - Office of Planning Coordination (Folder 536, Box 40)
  - Oil Company Letters (Folder 537, Box 40)
  - Olana (Folder 538, Box 40)
  - Old Foundry Site (Folder 539, Box 40)
  - Old Print Shop (Folder 540, Box 40)
  - Olympic National Park (Folder 541, Box 40)
  - Open Space Action (Folder 542, Box 40)
  - Open Space Action Committee (Folder 543, Box 40)
  - Opinion Poll 1964 (Folder 544, Box 40)
  - Orange County (Folder 545, Box 40)
  - Orange County and Dutchess County Garden Club (Folder 546, Box 40)
  - Orange County Data Book (Folder 547, Box 41)
  - Organizations: Lists of their Members (Folder 548, Box 41)
  - Osborn, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick (Folder 549, Box 41)
  - Osborne, Lithgow (Folder 550, Box 41)
  - Osborn, William H. (Folder 551, Box 41)
  - Ottinger, Richard L. (Folder 552, Box 41)
  - Ottinger Bill (Folder 553, Box 41)
  - Outdoor Recreation (Folder 554, Box 41)
  - P (Folder 555, Box 41)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission (Folder 556, Box 41)
  - Palisades Nature Association (Folder 557, Box 42)
  - Parklands (Folder 558, Box 42)
  - Peebles Island (Folder 559, Box 42)
  - Peekskill Garden Club (Folder 560, Box 42)
  - Pell, Herbert (Folder 561, Box 42)
  - Penobscot Basin Study (Folder 562, Box 42)
  - Pending (Folder 563, Box 42)
  - Perkins, George W. (Folder 564, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Correspondence (Folder 565, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Maps (Folder 566, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Newspaper Clippings (Folder 567, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Rowan, Anthony T. (Folder 568, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Traffic Survey (Folder 569, Box 42)
  - Phelps Project - Work (Folder 570, Box 42)
  - Philipse Manor Garden Club (Folder 571, Box 42)
  - Orange County Data Book (Folder 547, Box 41)
  - Organizations: Lists of their Members (Folder 548, Box 41)
  - Osborn, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick (Folder 549, Box 41)
  - Osborne, Lithgow (Folder 550, Box 41)
  - Osborn, William H. (Folder 551, Box 41)
  - Ottinger, Richard L. (Folder 552, Box 41)
  - Ottinger Bill (Folder 553, Box 41)
  - Outdoor Recreation (Folder 554, Box 41)
  - P (Folder 555, Box 41)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission (Folder 556, Box 41)
  - Philipstown Garden Club (Folder 572, Box 42)
  - Photographs (Folder 573, Box 42)
  - Piermont (Folder 574, Box 42)
  - Play - “Well of the World” (Folder 575, Box 42)
  - Policies and Procedures (Folder 576, Box 42)
  - Pollution (Folder 577, Box 42)
  - Pollution Abatement (Folder 578, Box 42)
  - Pollution Abatement - Charles A. Lasher Reports (Folder 579, Box 42)
  - Pollution Abatement Petition Letters (Folder 580, Box 42)
  - Pollution File Material (Folder 581, Box 42)
  - Pomeroy, Robert Watson (Folder 582, Box 42)
  - Pomeroy Hearings - Correspondence (Folder 583, Box 42)
  - Pomeroy Hearings Miscellaneous (Folder 584, Box 43)
  - Poughkeepsie Branch (Folder 585, Box 43)
  - Pomeroy Hearings - Press Releases (Folder 586, Box 43)
  - Pomeroy Hearings - Progress Reports (Folder 587, Box 43)
  - Pomeroy Hearings - Suggestions and Criticisms (Folder 588, Box 43)
  - Pomeroy Hearings - Speeches at Bear Mountain (Folder 589, Box 43)
  - Pough, Richard (Folder 590, Box 43)
  - Poughkeepsie Garden Club (Folder 591, Box 43)
  - Power Lines and Scenic Values in the Hudson River Valley (Folder 592, Box 43)
  - Preserving Historic America (Folder 593, Box 43)
  - Press Correspondence (Folder 594, Box 43)
  - Promotional Publicity (Folder 595, Box 43)
  - Property Acquisition (Folder 596, Box 43)
  - Prospective Members (Folder 597, Box 43)
  - Publicity (Folder 598, Box 43)
  - Pure Waters Play (Folder 599, Box 44)
  - Pure Waters Program (Folder 600, Box 44)
  - Putnam County (Folder 601, Box 44)
  - Putnam County Branch (Folder 602, Box 44)
  - Putnam County Data Book (Folder 603, Box 44)
  - Putnam County Historical Society (Folder 604, Box 44)
  - Quarrying (Folder 605, Box 44)
  - Questionnaires (Folder 606, Box 44)
  - R (Folder 607, Box 44)
  - Real Property Tax (Folder 608, Box 44)
  - Recreation (Folder 609, Box 44)
  - Recreation Proposal: Cornwall Pumped - Storage Project (Folder 610, Box 44)
  - Reese, Frances (Folder 611, Box 44)
  - Refuse Disposal and Waste Conversion Science Foundation (Folder 612, Box 44)
  - Regional Plan Association, Inc. (See Also Oversize) (Folder 613, Box 44)
  - Rensselaer County (Folder 614, Box 45)
  - Reports (Folder 615, Box 45)
  - Report on Pollution of the Hudson River and Its Tributaries (Folder 616, Box 45)
  - Resources for the Future, Inc. (Folder 617, Box 45)
  - “Restoration 1737” Van Allen House- Kinderhook (Folder 618, Box 45)
  - Rhinebeck Garden Club (Folder 619, Box 45)
  - River Keeper (Folder 620, Box 45)
  - “A River Needs Its Friends” (Folder 621, Box 45)
  - River Pollution and Improvements (Folder 622, Box 45)
  - Rockefeller, John D. Jr. (Folder 623, Box 45)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance (Folder 624, Box 45)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson (Folder 625, Box 45)
  - Rockland County Branch (Folder 626, Box 45)
  - Rockland County (Folder 627, Box 45)
  - Rockland County Conservation Association (Folder 628, Box 45)
  - Rockland County Data Book (Folder 629, Box 45)
  - Roden, William (Folder 630, Box 45)
  - Romaine, Victor (Folder 631, Box 45)
  - Roseton Plant of Central Hudson (Folder 632, Box 45)
  - Royal Bank of Canada (Folder 633, Box 45)
  - Rye- Oyster Bay Bridge (Folder 634, Box 45)
  - S (Folder 635, Box 46)
  - Sackett, Blanche Elizabeth (Folder 636, Box 46)
  - Safe, Clean Waters for New York State (Folder 637, Box 46)
  - Saugerties Lighthouse (Folder 638, Box 46)
  - Saugerties Powerboat Association (Folder 639, Box 46)
  - Save the Meadowlands Coalition (Folder 640, Box 46)
  - Save the Palisades Association (Folder 641, Box 46)
  - Saw Mill River Audubon Society (Folder 642, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson News (Folder 643, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1963 (Folder 644, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1964 (Folder 645, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1965 (Folder 646, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1966 (Folder 647, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1967 (Folder 648, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1968 (Folder 649, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1969 (Folder 650, Box 46)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference 1970 - 1973 and Undated (Folder 651, Box 46)
  - Scenic Sites (Folder 652, Box 46)
  - Scenic Sites - Hudson River View Project (Folder 653, Box 46)
  - Schermerhorn, Richard (Folder 654, Box 46)
  - Schumacher and Company (Folder 655, Box 46)
  - Seagears, Clayton B. (Folder 656, Box 46)
  - Senate House (Folder 657, Box 46)
  - “Sewage Along the Hudson” (Folder 658, Box 47)
  - Shade Swamp Sanctuary (Folder 659, Box 47)
  - Shadow on the River (Folder 660, Box 47)
  - Sierra Club (Folder 661, Box 47)
  - Sleepy Hollow Restorations - Sunnyside and Van Cortlandt Manor (Folder 662, Box 47)
  - Smoke Abatement (Folder 663, Box 47)
  - Soil Conservation (Folder 664, Box 47)
  - Sonotone Company (Folder 665, Box 47)
  - Speaker’s Material re Society (Folder 666, Box 47)
  - Spring Valley Water Company (Folder 667, Box 47)
  - State of New York Council of Environmental Advisors (Folder 668, Box 47)
  - State of New York Department of Law (Folder 669, Box 47)
  - State of New York Office of Planning Services (Folder 670, Box 47)
  - State of New York Public Service Commission (Folder 671, Box 47)
  - Stewardship: The Land, the Landowner and the Metropolis (Folder 672, Box 48)
  - Stevens Castle (Folder 673, Box 48)
  - Stewart Airport (Folder 674, Box 48)
  - Stickles, Lester D. (Folder 675, Box 48)
  - Stillman, Calvin W. (Folder 676, Box 48)
  - Stony Point Project (Folder 677, Box 48)
  - Storm King (Folder 678, Box 48)
  - Student Conservation Association, Inc. (Folder 679, Box 48)
  - Studies of Similar Areas (Folder 680, Box 48)
  - Study of Needs for Sewage Works (Folder 681, Box 48)
  - Surveys (Folder 682, Box 48)
  - T (Folder 683, Box 48)
  - Taconic State Park Commission (Folder 684, Box 48)
  - The Tappan Zee (Folder 685, Box 48)
  - Tappan Zee Historical Society (Folder 686, Box 48)
  - Tappan Zee Civic Association re Thruway and Bridge (Folder 687, Box 48)
  - Tarrytown Branch (Folder 688, Box 48)
  - Tarrytown Luncheon (Folder 689, Box 49)
  - Tarrytown, New York (Folder 690, Box 49)
  - Tarrytown Waterfront Dump (Folder 691, Box 49)
  - Tax Exempt Properties (Folder 692, Box 49)
  - Temporary State Commission on Environmental Impact of Major Public Utility Facilities (Folder 693, Box 49)
  - Temporary State Commission to Study the Catskills (Folder 694, Box 49)
  - Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks (Folder 695, Box 49)
  - Thermal Pollution (Folder 696, Box 49)
  - “Thermal Pollution and Aquatic Life” (Folder 697, Box 49)
  - Thompson Pond (Folder 698, Box 49)
  - Thruway - Turnpike Link (Folder 699, Box 49)
  - “Time is Now” (Folder 700, Box 49)
  - Times Herald Record (Folder 701, Box 49)
  - Tontine Coffee House (Folder 702, Box 49)
  - Trainor, Joan (Folder 703, Box 49)
  - U (Folder 704, Box 50)
  - Ulster County (Folder 705, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Air Pollution - Correspondence (Folder 706, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Air Pollution - Meeting Minutes (Folder 707, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Air Pollution - Public Law (Folder 708, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Air Pollution - Work (Folder 709, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Clean Air Correspondence (Folder 710, Box 50)
  - Ulster Count Conference on Natural Beauty (Folder 711, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Data Book (Folder 712, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Extension Service Association (Folder 713, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Garden Club (Folder 714, Box 50)
  - Ulster County Historical Society (Folder 715, Box 50)
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Correspondence (Folder 716, Box 50)
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Notices (Folder 717, Box 50)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare: Division of Water Supply and Pollution Control (Folder 718, Box 50)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare: Public Health Service (Folder 719, Box 50)
  - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (Folder 720, Box 50)
  - U.S. Post Office (Folder 721, Box 50)
  - U.S. Senate - Bills (Folder 722, Box 50)
  - V (Folder 723, Box 50)
  - Vanderbilt Mansion (Folder 724, Box 50)
  - Vermont (Folder 725, Box 50)
  - W (Folder 726, Box 51)
  - Warthin, A. Scott Jr. (Folder 727, Box 51)
  - Washburn, Mrs. Frank B. (Folder 728, Box 51)
  - Washington- Carleton Celebration (Folder 729, Box 51)
  - Water Chestnut in the Hudson River (Folder 730, Box 51)
  - Water for Recreation (Folder 731, Box 51)
  - Water for the Future of Long Island, New York (Folder 732, Box 51)
  - Water Pollution - Correspondence (Folder 733, Box 51)
  - Water Pollution - Current Status (Folder 734, Box 51)
  - Water Pollution - Detergents (Folder 735, Box 51)
  - Water Pollution - Film Scripts (Folder 736, Box 51)
  - Water Pollution - General (Folder 737, Box 51)
  - W (Folder 726, Box 52)
  - Warthin, A. Scott Jr. (Folder 727, Box 52)
  - Washburn, Mrs. Frank B. (Folder 728, Box 52)
  - Washington- Carleton Celebration (Folder 729, Box 52)
  - Water Chestnut in the Hudson River (Folder 730, Box 52)
  - Water for Recreation (Folder 731, Box 52)
  - Water for the Future of Long Island, New York (Folder 732, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution - Correspondence (Folder 733, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution - Current Status (Folder 734, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution - Detergents (Folder 735, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution - Film Scripts (Folder 736, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution - General (Folder 737, Box 52)
  - Water Pollution Miscellaneous (Folder 738, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - National Council for Stream Improvement (Folder 739, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Newspaper Clippings (Folder 740, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Press Releases (Folder 741, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Publications (Folder 742, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Pure Waters Program (Folder 743, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Reference File (Folder 744, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution - Sewage (Folder 745, Box 53)
  - Water Pollution Control Act (Folder 746, Box 54)
  - Water Resources Reference (Folder 747, Box 54)
  - Water Spectrum (Folder 748, Box 54)
  - Waterford Flight (Folder 749, Box 54)
  - Watersheds (Folder 750, Box 54)
  - Watson, Thomas J. (Folder 751, Box 54)
  - Webb, Mrs. Vanderbilt (Folder 752, Box 54)
  - West Point Stack (Folder 753, Box 54)
  - Westchester County (Folder 754, Box 54)
  - Westchester County Conservation Association (Folder 755, Box 54)
  - Westchester County Historical Society (Folder 756, Box 54)
  - Westchester County Park Commission (Folder 757, Box 54)
  - Wightman, Mrs. Gordon (Folder 758, Box 54)
  - Wilderness Society (Folder 759, Box 54)
  - William Church Osborn Marine Park Committee (Folder 760, Box 54)
  - Williams Project (Folder 761, Box 55)
  - Williamsburg, Virginia (Folder 762, Box 55)
  - Women’s Unit News (Folder 763, Box 55)
  - “Wonder of Water” (Folder 764, Box 55)
  - XYZ (Folder 765, Box 55)
  - Yacht and Boat Clubs Along the Hudson (Folder 766, Box 55)
  - YMCA - Northfield League, Inc. (Folder 767, Box 55)
  - Yonkers Museum of Science and Arts (Folder 768, Box 55)
  - Yorktown Garden Club (Folder 769, Box 55)
  - Zoning and Planning (Folder 770, Box 55)
  - Zoning and Planning Survey 1957 (Folder 771, Box 55)
- 2. Scrapbooks, 1939 - 1959; 2; 5 linear foot 56 - 61 772 - 781
  A collection of various newspaper articles organized in scrapbooks dealing with issues of the environment and legislation pertaining to that which the Society was interested in.
  Original Order (chronological/ topical)
  - Scrapbook 1 1939 - 1947 (Folder 772, Box 56)
  - Scrapbook 2 1948 - 1957 (Folder 773, Box 57)
  - Scrapbook 3 1955 - 1959 (Folder 774, Box 58)
  - Scrapbook 4 1958 - 1959 (Folder 775, Box 59)